现在这个模块是完全可选的
now this module is completely optional
但如果你正在学习灵药
but in case you're learning elixir
因为你接下来要去凤凰城
because you're on your way to Phoenix next
好吧，我们有好消息要告诉你
well we have good news for you
它会看起来很熟悉
it's gonna look pretty familiar
是的，这有点像学习一门新语言
yeah it's a bit like learning a new language
国际旅行前
before an international trip
你选择了语言课程
you pick up a language course
你学习了一些常用的单词和短语
you learn some common words and phrases
然后你在办公室周围练习k
and then you practice them around the office k
然后当你出现在你的目的地
then when you turn up at your destination
有些景象和声音感觉很熟悉
some of the sights and sounds feel familiar
所以让我们先来看一个 Phoenix 应用程序
so let's start by looking at a Phoenix app
只是让你不认为我们有
just so you don't think we have
我们袖手旁观的任何技巧
any tricks up our sleeve
我们将生成一个 Phoenix 应用程序
we'll generate a Phoenix app
从头开始，看看我们得到了什么
from scratch and see what we get
免费
for free
现在我已经在这台电脑上安装了 Phoenix
now I already have Phoenix installed on this computer
检查笔记
check the notes
如果您需要安装说明
if you need installation instructions
在您的计算机上进行设置
to get it set up on your computer
并生成应用程序
and to generate the app
我们以应用程序的名义说 mix p new
we say mix p new in the name of the app
在这种情况下，我们将称之为避难所
in this case we're going to call it refuge
现在只要确保
now just make sure
你不在调查目录中
that you're not in the survey directory
当你运行它时，你可以在其他任何地方
when you run this you can be anywhere else
我现在在一个空的应用程序目录中
I'm in an empty apps directory right now
然后继续生成了一堆代码
and that went ahead and generated a bunch of code
然后问我们
and then asked us
如果我们要安装依赖项
if we want to install the dependencies
一定要继续这样做
sure go ahead and do that
然后它将下载依赖项
then it's going to download the dependencies
并编译它们并得到
and compile them and get
一切都设置好了
everything set up
并通过视频的魔力
and through the magic of video
我们会加快速度
we'll speed this up a bit
然后我们会改变
then we'll change
进入它创建的那个避难所目录
into that refuge directory that it created
我们要生成一些脚手架代码
and we'll want to generate some scaffold code
用于创建
for creating
阅读更新和删除我们的熊资源
reading updating and deleting our bear resources
是的，凤凰城有许多发电机
yeah Phoenix has a number of generators
我们将生成一个 html 应用程序，让我们说 mix p
we're going to generate an html app so let's say mix p
dot gm html 然后是上下文的名称
dot gm html then once the name of a context
我稍后会解释，我们将调用我们的
I'll explain that a bit later we're going to call our
野生的东西
wild things
资源的名称将是熊
the name of the resource is going to be bear
然后它想要它的复数名称
then it wants the plural name it'll be bears
然后我们给它资源的属性
and then we give it attributes for the resource
所以我们会有一个名字
so we're going to have a name
那将是一个字符串
that's going to be a string
类型将是一个字符串
a type will be a string
我们会冬眠
and we'll have hibernating
这将是一个布尔值
which will be a boolean
它继续生成所有文件
and it went ahead and generated all the files
用于管理该资源
for managing that resource
所以现在我们将继续在我们的编辑器中打开它
so now we'll go ahead and open it in our editor
我正在使用崇高
and I'm using sublime
我在左边有我们的调查应用程序
and I have our survey app on the left
和右边的 Phoenix 应用程序
and the Phoenix app on the right
让我们直接进入 Phoenix 应用的控制器
let's dive right into the controller of the Phoenix app
是的，它是在实时目录中完成的
yeah it's done in the live directory
有一个目录叫避难所
there's a directory called refuge
然后如果我们进入网络内部
and then if we go inside of web
好吧，有一个名为 controllers 的子目录
well there's a sub directory called controllers
我会再打开一点
I'll open that up just a little bit more
所以我们可以看到
so we can see it
还有裸控制器
and there's the bare controller
不仅节省空间
and didn't just save space
我要关闭那个侧边栏
I'm going to close that sidebar
就像我们左边的裸控制器一样
and just like our bare controller on the left
它是一个定义
it's a module that defines
称为动作的函数
functions called actions
处理不同的请求
to handle different requests
所以从这里的顶部开始，第一行是这个
so starting from the top here the first line is this
使用线，这是一个元编程咒语
use line and it's a meta programming incantation
这需要这个网络模块
which requires this web module
这反过来又注入了一些代码
which in turn injects some code
进入我们的控制器
into our controller
现在这是凤凰城特有的东西
now this is a Phoenix specific thing
别担心
don't worry about it
然后它给这个狂野的东西起了别名
and then it aliases this wild things
稍后我们将看到的模块
module which we'll look at in a minute
然后我们有索引动作
then we have the index action
现在在凤凰城
now in Phoenix
每个动作需要两个
each action takes two
Phoenix 框架提供的参数
parameters which the Phoenix framework provides
动作运行时
when the action is run
第一个参数始终是 con nn
the first parameter is always co n n
这是连接的缩写
it's an abbreviation for connection
它类似于我们的骗局
it's similar to our con
这是一个结构
it's a structure
包含有关请求的信息
that holds information about the request
第二个参数是
the second parameter is
para 是一个包含任何请求参数的映射
para which is a map that holds any request parameters
类似于我们的参数的地图
similar to our param's map
现在这种情况下的索引操作不使用
now the index action in this case doesn't use
参数
the parameters
所以它使用下划线
so it uses underscore
参数，这样我们就不会收到编译器警告
parameters so that we don't get a compiler warning
关于它没有被使用
about it not being used
现在我们的索引操作只需要转换
now our index action just takes conv
因为第一个参数没有第二个参数
as the first parameter doesn't have a second parameter
因为我们没有在我们的索引操作中使用 para
because we don't use the para in our index action
但你知道如何通过这些
but you know how to pass those through
如果你想那样做
if you wanted to do that
就像我们的应用程序调用狂野的东西
just like our app calls wild things
列出熊以获取所有熊
list bears to get all the bears
如果我们查看 Phoenix 应用程序
if we look in the Phoenix app
索引操作的第一行做同样的事情
the first line in index action does the same thing
我们有一个模块wild things
we've got a module wild things
并调用一个函数来列出熊和
and calls a function to list bears and
两者都返回熊市名单
both return a list of bear struck
然后它调用 render 传递 conn
then it calls render passing conn
它还传递了模板名称索引 html
and it also passes the template name index html
现在凤凰使用了一个略
now Phoenix uses a slightly
与我们不同的命名约定
different naming convention than ours
但两个模板都呈现 html
but both templates render html
然后第三个参数是绑定
and then the third parameter is the bindings
所以他们要把熊绑在熊身上
so they're going to bind bears to bears
就像我们在这里调用渲染时所做的那样
just like we did over here when we called our render
现在让我们更深一层
now let's dig one level deeper
进入这个野物模块
into this wild things module
再次打开侧边栏
open up the sidebar again
它在一个名为 wild things 的目录中
it's down here in a directory called wild things
还有一个狂野的东西
and there's a wild things ex
我们将在我们的调查应用程序中做同样的事情
and we'll do the same over here in our survey app
我们只是在调查中的所有内容
we just have everything under survey
还有我们的野生动物模块
and there's our wild things module
所以如果我们看看野生动物
so if we look at the wild things
Phoenix 生成的模块
module generated by Phoenix
这是创建阅读的简单抽象
it's a simple abstraction for creating reading
在我们的案例中更新和删除资源
updating and deleting a resource bears in our case
现在，如果您查看 Phoenix 文档
now if you look to the Phoenix documentation
他们会把这件事称为上下文
they're going to refer to this thing as a context
评论说这是野外的边界
and the comment says that it's a boundary for the wild
事物系统
things system
所以基本上这是一个数据访问层
so basically this is a data access layer
它封装
it encapsulates
一切与
everything related to
让熊创造熊
getting bears creating bears
更新熊和删除熊
updating bears and deleting bears
所以如果我们看这个列表就在这里
so if we look at this list bears function right here
它在传递的熊下面调用
it calls below passing bear
那么 re 模块是
well the re module is part of the
ecto 库，这是数据库说唱歌手库
ecto library and this is the database rapper library
凤凰使用
used by Phoenix
repo 表示与数据库的连接
and repo represents a connection to a database which
默认情况下将是
by default is going to be
后风险数据库
a post risk database
所以打电话给代表
so calling rep
查询数据库以获取我们应用程序中的所有熊
queries the database to fetch all the bears in our app
我们只有一个内存数据库
we just have an in memory database
所以我们的列表熊只返回一个熊的列表
so our list bears just returns a list of bears
然后回到这里
then back over here
如果我们再向下滚动一点
if we scroll down a little bit further
他们有一个调用 repo dot get 的 get bear 函数
they have a get bear function that calls repo dot get
传递 id 中的熊
passing the bear in the id
这将发出一个数据库查询来查找
which will issue a database query to find
具有给定 ID 的熊
the bear with the given id
和我们的get bear很相似
it's pretty similar to our get bear
除了我们使用电子邮件
except we're using email
找找
find to find
熊名单中的熊
the bear within the list of bears
具有匹配的 id
that has that matching id
现在你注意到如果我们向下滚动和狂野的东西
now you notice if we scroll down over and wild things
他们有创造熊的功能
they have a function for creating a bear
有更新熊的功能
there's a function for updating a bear
以及从数据库中删除熊
and also for deleting a bear from the database
现在让我们走吧
now let's go
看看那个索引模板看看发生了什么
have a look at that index template to see what's going
在凤凰应用程序中
on in there so in the Phoenix app
在 web 目录下，您会找到一个模板
under the web directory you'll find a template
子目录
sub directory
然后它由控制器组织这些
and then it has these organized by the controller
所以裸控制器的所有模板都是
so all the templates for the bare controller are
在裸子目录下
under the bare sub directory
还有那个索引
and there's the index for that
你注意到他们使用命名约定索引
and you notice they use the naming convention index
那个 html 前
that html ex
这只是与我们使用的命名约定不同
it's just a different naming convention than we used
这里的意图是
the intent here is
看名字就知道
you know by looking at the name
这会生成 html
that this generates html
因此在这里打开我们的索引模板
thus open up our index template over here
在模板中
down in templates
在那里
there it is
嘿，以同样的方式检查一下
hey check this out in the same way
我们用一个理解来
we use a comprehension to
遍历所有的熊
loop through all the bears
然后我们使用小于 % 等于
and then we're using less than % equals
好吧，他们在这里做同样的事情
well they're doing the same thing here
对熊有一种理解
there's a comprehension for bear
注意熊在它前面有一个符号
notice the bears has an at sign before it
这就是 Phoenix 设置数据的方式
this is just the way Phoenix sets up data
在行动中
in the actions
所以要访问绑定到熊名的值
so to get access to the value bound to the bears name
你必须在凤凰城的熊市使用
you have to use at bears in Phoenix
然后在那个循环里面
and then inside of that loop
他们使用相同的
they use the same
获取熊的所有属性的语法
syntax to get all the attributes of the bear
到目前为止，这一切都很熟悉
so far this is all pretty familiar
现在让我们回到控制器
now let's go back to the controller
熊控制器在这里
bear controller here
和这里的裸控制器
and the bare controller here
让我们看看这个
let's have a look at this
在 Phoenix 生成的应用程序中显示操作
show action in the Phoenix generated app
这是并排放置的
here is put them side by side
你会注意到就像我们的表演动作
and you notice just like our show action
第二个参数
the second parameters
这些 para，他们正在使用模式匹配
these para and they're using pattern matching
提取这个id
to extract this id
然后他们转身打电话
then they turn around and call
得到熊与那个 id 得到熊袭击
get bear with that id to get the bear struck
然后他们用模板 show html 调用 render
then they call render with the template show html
并将熊作为绑定值传递
and pass the bear as a bound value
与我们提取 id 的方式相同
the same way we extract the id
从我们的野生动物模块中获取熊
get the bear from our wild things module
并渲染显示模板
and render the show template
现在这里的箱子动作怎么样
now what about this crate action over here
在我们的应用程序中很好
well in our app
我们实际上并没有在数据库中创建熊
we didn't actually create a bear in the database
这有点超出本课程的范围
that's sort of outside the scope of this course
但是如果我们看
but if we look at
生成的 crate 动作是如何做到的
how the generated crate action does it
这是熟悉的代码
it's familiar code
我们注意到它的模式匹配
we notice its pattern matching
在对面
on the para
将熊 para 提取到这个变量中
to extract the bear para into this variable
这些 para 进来的方式是它们是嵌套的
and the way these para come in is they're nested
在一个叫熊的钥匙下
under a key called bear
所以这是另一张地图中的一张地图
so it's a map inside of another map
然后他们调用创建
then they call the create
熊婴儿车的熊功能
bear function with those bear prams
这可能成功也可能失败
and that can succeed or fail
所以他们使用 case 表达式
so they're using a case expression
然后他们可以进行模式匹配
and then they can pattern match
关于成败
on the success or failure
所以如果它成功了，我们将得到一个 ok atom
so if it succeeds we're going to get an ok atom
然后我们会有一只熊
and then we're going to have a bear
在这种情况下，他们会建立联系
in that case they take the connection
他们打电话给
and they call
put flash on it 放一条闪光信息
put flash on it to put a flash message
在那个连接里面
inside of that connection
这只是添加了连接的额外信息
this just adds extra information of the connection
就像我们插入函数一样
in the same way that we plugged in functions
使用日志和跟踪之类的东西
using things like log and track
然后它重定向到显示动作
and then it redirects to the show action
展示新熊
to show the new bear
否则如果创建熊失败
otherwise if creating the bear fails
然后我们得到这个元组和模式匹配
then we get this tuple and pattern match on it
我们得到一个错误
we get an error
然后我们有一个叫做改变的东西
and then we have this thing called a change
设置它们的模式匹配
set that they pattern match on
那改变
and that change
set 将包括要显示的任何验证错误
set will include any validation errors to be displayed
所以他们提取变更集
so they extract the change set
然后他们渲染新模板
and then they render the new template
给它改变
giving it the change
设置以便它可以提取验证错误
set so it can pull out the validation errors
如果你滚动浏览这个文件
and if you scroll through this file
你会看到生成器实现了
you'll see that the generator implemented
其他安静的动作
other restful actions
喜欢编辑这里有更新
like edit there's update down here
有一个删除操作
there's a delete action
但这里真的没有新的语法或概念
but there's really no new syntax or concepts here
路由器更有趣所以让我们跳过去
the router is more interesting so let's hop over there
路由器在目录 web 中结束
the router is over in the directory web
如果你向下滚动这里有一个文件路由器 ex
if you scroll down here there's a file router ex
只是为了比较
and just for comparison
这边
over here
我要打开我们的处理程序，因为它有我们的
I'm going to open up our handler because that has our
里面的路由功能
route function inside of it
现在这个路由器模块看起来很漂亮
now this router module looks pretty
不同于我们见过的其他模块
different than other modules that we've seen
而不是定义函数
rather than defining functions
它使用宏
it uses macros
所以感觉更像是一种特定领域的语言
so it feels more like a domain specific language
并且宏得到扩展
and the macros get expanded
在编译时进入函数
into functions at compile time
现在这里发生了很多事情
now there's a lot going on in here
所以让我们分解一下
so let's break it down
暂时忘记这些管道
forget about these pipelines for just a minute
我们会回到那些
we'll come back to those
让我们在这里专注于这条路线
let's focus on this route right here
所以它匹配路径斜杠的 git 请求
so it matches a git request for the path slash
然后它会调用页面控制器
and then it's going to call the page controllers
处理该请求的索引操作
index action to handle that request
现在凤凰生成页面
now Phoenix generated the page
默认情况下 index 动作中的控制器
controller in the index action by default
因为它只想显示一个欢迎页面
because it just wants to display a welcome page and
有些东西
have something
在那里供人们查看
there for people to look at
但我们想要一个列出承载的路线
but we want a route for listing bearers
所以我要复制这个
so I'm just going to copy this
把它放在这条路线下面
put it below this route
当我们去砍熊的时候
and when we go to slash bears
我们想运行我们的熊控制器
we want to run our bear controller
立即索引操作
index action now
我提到这个模块大量使用
I mentioned that this module makes heavy use
宏和
of macros and
get 是一个宏
get is a macro
它会在编译时扩展
and it's going to get expanded at compile time
进入一个名为 match 的函数
into a function called match
它看起来像这样
it looks something like this
我只是将它粘贴到这里之外
I'm just going to paste it outside of here
所以该函数称为匹配
so the function is called match
它
it
接受他们的联系或对话
takes a conn that's their connection or conversation
是否在 hdp 动词上进行模式匹配
did it pattern matches on the hdp verb
在这种情况下，这将是一个得到
in this case it's going to be a get
因为我们曾经到达那里
because we used get there
然后第三个参数是
and then the third parameter is
他们模式匹配的列表
a list that they pattern match on
这是斜线熊的路径
and this is the path slash bears
所以 match 函数需要三个参数
so the match function takes three arguments
如果我们查看斜线熊的路线功能
if we look over at our route function for slash bears
我们只接受一个论点
we're just taking one argument
这是 co 和 v 我们的联系
it's the co and v our connection
然后我们进行模式匹配
and then we pattern match on
该连接的内部是什么
what's inside of that connection
所以我们是模式匹配
so we're pattern matching
对话地图中的任何内容
whatever's inside of the conversation map
作为一个论点
as one argument
以及它们的模式匹配
and their pattern matching on the
动词和路径分别是两个单独的参数
verb and the path separately is two separate arguments
但这没什么大不了的
but that's no big deal
现在您知道如何进行模式匹配了
now that you know how to pattern match
你可以在一个参数上进行模式匹配
you could pattern match on one argument that has
地图内的一切
everything inside of a map
或者您可以在单独的参数上进行模式匹配
or you could pattern match on separate arguments
这是六个半打的其他
it's six and one half a dozen of the other
所以我要摆脱这个
so I'm going to get rid of this
因为这又是在编译时生成的
because again that's generated at compile time
通过宏，但假设我们想要完整的
by the macro but let's say we wanted the full
管理熊资源的补充途径
complementary route to manage a bear resource
好吧，我们可以这样做
well we could do this
通过在这里放一堆路线
by putting a bunch of routes in here
我只是要粘贴一个
and I'm just going to paste in a
我已经有的清单
list I already have
每一个都是一个宏
and each of these is a macro
这会扩大
that's going to get expanded
进入匹配函数
into a match function
所以我们最终会得到八个
so we're going to end up with eight
多子句匹配函数
multi clause match functions
我们知道多子句函数的行为
and we know how multi clause functions behave
elixir 尝试从上到下匹配它们
elixir tries to match them from top to bottom
和第一个
and the first
匹配动词和路径的子句将被运行
clause that matches the verb and the path will be run
现在正如你所料
now as you might expect
有一条捷径可以添加所有这些宁静的路线
there's a shortcut to adding all these restful routes
所以如果我们把它注释掉
so if we comment this out
这样做的速记方法是说资源
shorthand way of doing this is to say resources
斜线熊
slash bears
然后是裸控制器
and then bare controller
这本身就是一个将要扩展的宏
and that itself is a macro that's going to expand
给我们所有人
to give us all
match函数的八个子句
eight clauses of the match function
所以现在让我们回头看看这个
so now let's double back and look at this
管道顶部的东西在这里
pipeline stuff at the top here
记住我们有自己的管道
and remember we have our own pipeline
在这个句柄函数中
over in this handle function
我们正在使用管道运算符来做到这一点
we're using the pipe operator to do that
它管道请求
it pipes the request
通过我们编写的各种函数
through various functions we've written
而 Phoenix 有两条独立的管道
while Phoenix has two separate pipelines
其中一个叫做浏览器
one of them's called browser
其中一个叫做 api
and one of them's called api
他们在内部执行不同的转换
and they perform different transformations inside
这个用于浏览器
this one for the browsers
比 api 更复杂一点
a little bit more involved than the one for the api
因为他们有不同的需求
because they have different needs
而不是使用管道运算符
instead of using the pipe operator
他们使用这个插件功能
they use this plug function
就在这儿
right here
然后他们给它一个函数的名字
and then they give it the name of a function
所以这会插入接受功能
so this plugs the accepts function
获取会话功能等
the fetch session function and so on
但它基本上是一样的
but it's basically the same thing it's a
转换功能管道
pipeline of transformation functions
他们被应用于请求
they get applied to the request
然后因为这些管道有名字
then because these pipelines have names
如果我们在范围斜线下往下看
if we look down here under scope slash
它说通过浏览器管道
it says pipe through browser
因此基于浏览器的请求通过管道传递
so browser based requests get piped through
这条管道
this pipeline
意思是
which means
与这些路由匹配的任何请求都将具有
any of the requests that match these routes will have
已经通过了这条管道
already gone through this pipeline
同样，如果您向下滚动一点
likewise if you scroll down a little bit further
有一个范围
there is a scope for
api 并通过 api 管道传输
api and it gets piped through the api pipeline
现在我们才刚刚触及凤凰的表面
now we've barely scratched the surface of Phoenix
它是一个全栈 Web 框架
it's a full stack web framework
毕竟有很多花里胡哨
after all with lots of bells and whistles
但希望这个快速演练能给你更多
but hopefully this quick walkthrough has given you more
起航前的信心
confidence before setting sail
为了凤凰火热的土地
for the fiery land of Phoenix